<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Yue Wu</title>
        <link>https://yue-here.github.io/</link>
        <description>Yue Wu</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>yuewu[at]slac.stanford.edu (Yue Wu)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>yuewu[at]slac.stanford.edu (Yue Wu)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://yue-here.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Training T5 models and generating text</title>
    <link>https://yue-here.github.io/t5/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Yue Wu</author>
    <guid>https://yue-here.github.io/t5/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[For the language-to-language components of this JACS does not exist, I chose Google&rsquo;s T5 (text-to-text transfer transformer) as a recent cutting-edge text sequence to sequence model.
I had already scraped all the JACS titles and abstracts, so training data was readily available. The first task was to generate somewhat-convincing abstracts from titles to increase the entertainment value of TJDNE.
As abstracts have a maximum length, I wanted to make sure that a whole abstract would be included in T5&rsquo;s maximum input length of 512 tokens so that end-of-sequence locations could be determined.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Abstract2title</title>
    <link>https://yue-here.github.io/abstract2title/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Yue Wu</author>
    <guid>https://yue-here.github.io/abstract2title/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Many people enjoyed title2abstract from the this JACS does not exist project so I inverted the training parameters for a quick follow up. Presenting abstract2title: You can also test the title2abstract and toc2title apps in my previous post.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>This JACS does not exist</title>
    <link>https://yue-here.github.io/thisjacsdoesnotexist/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:56:40 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Yue Wu</author>
    <guid>https://yue-here.github.io/thisjacsdoesnotexist/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[An imaginary abstract generated at thisJACSdoesnotexist.com In academic chemistry, authors submit a promotional table-of-contents (ToC) image when publishing research papers in most journals. These fascinate me as they are one of the few places where unfettered self expression is tolerated, if not condoned. (See e.g. TOC ROFL, of which I am a multiple inductee)
In general, though, ToC images follow a fairly consistent visual language, with distinct conventions followed in different subfields.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
